It takes two to make it … The big two.
The Getaway is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Sam Peckinpah.
A recently released ex-convict and his loyal wife go
on the run after a heist goes wrong.
Carter "Doc" McCoy, played by Steve McQueen.
Carol McCoy, played by Ali MacGraw.
Jack Beynon, played by Ben Johnson.
Fran Clinton, played by Sally Struthers.
Rudy Butler, played by Al Lettieri.
Cowboy, played by Slim Pickens.
The Getaway is a 1972 American action-thriller film
based on the 1958 novel by Jim Thompson.
The film was directed by Sam Peckinpah and written by Walter Hill, and stars Steve
McQueen, Ali MacGraw, Ben Johnson, Al Lettieri, and Sally Struthers.
The plot follows imprisoned mastermind robber Carter "Doc" McCoy, whose wife Carol
conspires for his release on the condition they rob a bank in Texas.
A double-cross follows the crime, and the McCoys are forced to flee to
Mexico with the police and criminals in hot pursuit.
Peter Bogdanovich, whose The Last Picture Show impressed McQueen and producer
David Foster, was originally hired as the director of The Getaway.
Thompson came on board to write the screenplay, but creative differences ensued between him
and McQueen, and Thompson was subsequently fired,  along with Bogdanovich.
Writing and directing duties eventually went to
Hill and Peckinpah, respectively.
Principal photography commenced February 7, 1972, on location in Texas.
The film reunited McQueen and Peckinpah, who had worked together on the
relatively unprofitable Junior Bonner, released the same year.
The Getaway premiered December 19, 1972.
Despite the negative reviews it received upon release, numerous
retrospective critics have reevaluated the film positively.
A box-office hit earning over $36 million, it was the eighth-highest-grossing film of 1972, and one
of the most financially successful productions of Peckinpah's and McQueen's careers.
A film remake of the same name starring Alec Baldwin
and Kim Basinger was released in 1994.
The film explores themes of robbery, based on novel
or book, texas, heist, con artist.
The tone is dark and intense.